### Simon Kapitza

Quantitative & Applied Ecology Group (QAEco)
The University of Melbourne, Parkville, VIC, 3010
□ +61 412 914 876 ⋈ simon.kapitza.research@gmail.com

I am a global change ecologist researching interactions between socioeconomic and biophysical drivers of biodiversity change. My key strength is in interdisciplinary thinking to understand, capture and predict the impact of global transitions of the anthropocene on ecosystems, biodiversity and species.

### Skills

Data Analysis  Leadership	Proficient R user with experience in knitr, sweave, and RMarkdown, as well as integration of basic C++ via the RCpp package. Particularly experienced with very large spatial data sets and parallel processing (MaxEnt, Regression Trees, Linear Mixed Models). GitHub for version control. Intermediate experience with Python, SQL, ArcGIS, QGIS. Initiating and leading interdisciplinary research in our most recent project. Currently planning
skills Languages	research collaborations with institutes in Europe, with three scheduled seminars.  German ●●● English ●●● Spanish ●●○ French ●○○
Education	
2017 - present	PhD - Science University of Melbourne Supervisors: Prof Brendan Wintle, Dr Nick Golding Project: Global integrated assessment of biophysical and socioeconomic drivers of biodiversity change
2013 - 2016	MSc - Environmental Sciences (High Distinction), Albert-Ludwigs-Universitaet Freiburg Supervisors: Prof Carsten Dormann, Prof Brendan Wintle Project: Alleviating climate change uncertainty through improved modelling: Australian Great
	Desert Skinks under a changing fire regime (in collaboration with QAEco)
2009 - 2013	BSc Hon - Environmental Science and Politics University of Stirling Supervisor: Prof Daisy Dent
	Project: Rural Livelihoods in Changing Contexts: Causes and Impacts of Deforestation in Ta Veaeng District, Cambodia
2011 - 2012	Study Abroad University of Sydney
Presentations	5
2019	The economy, climate change and biodiversity
2010	Biogeography Colloquium, Humboldt University of Berlin
2018	Integrating drivers of change: an assessment of bio-physical and socio-economic climate change impacts on species habitat
	Australian Ecological Society Conference, Brisbane
	British Ecological Society Annual Meeting, Birmingham
	Accounting for socio-economic impacts in biodiversity modelling
	British Ecological Society Quantitative Ecology Spatial Interest Group conference, St. Andrews  Assessing direct and indirect impacts of climate change on bird habitat
	Poster, International Statistical Ecology Conference, St. Andrews  Indirect impacts of climate change on future bird habitat in Vietnam and Australia
	PhD confirmation seminar, School of BioSciences, University of Melbourne
	Comparing the biophysical and economic impacts of climate change on biodiversity Visiting scholar seminar, Helmholtz Institute for Zoology and Wildlife Research, Berlin
2017	Accounting for socioeconomic drivers of biodiversity change: A novel integrated assessment framework
2016	Seminar, Quantitative & Applied Ecology Group, University of Melbourne  Alleviating climate change uncertainty through improved modelling: Great Desert Skinks
	under a changing fire regime  MSc completion seminar, School of BioSciences, University of Melbourne

# Workshops

2019	CBRI Grand Challenges
	University of Melbourne Computational Biology Research Initiative
2018	Spatial Point Pattern Analysis
	Australian Research Council Centre of Excellence for Mathematical and Statistical Frontiers
	Combining Different Data Types In a Single Model
	International Statistical Ecology Conference 2018

### **Publications**

**Kapitza, S.**, Ha, P. V., Golding, N., Kompas, T, Cadenhead, N. C. R., Bal, P., Wintle, B.A., Assessing biophysical and socio-economic impacts of climate change on biodiversity (under review)

**Kapitza, S.**, Golding, N., Improved spatially-explicit land-use change modelling to predict future land use and biodiversity outcomes (in prep)

**Kapitza, S.**, Cadenhead, N., Wintle, B., Alleviating climate change uncertainty through improved modelling: Great Desert Skinks under a changing fire regime (in prep)

# Awards and scholarships

2018	Wiley Award for Best Poster, International Statistical Ecology Conference, St. Andrews
	Science Abroad Travelling Scholarship, University of Melbourne (AUD 1500)
	Financial Support for Research or Conference Travel, University of Melbourne (AUD 2000)
	Drummond Travel Award (AUD 1500)
2017	Australian Research Council Discovery top-up grant (AUD 21,000)
	Melbourne International Research Scholarship (AUD 120,000)
2015	DAAD PROMOS Scholarship grant (2300 EUR)

### Academic activities

2019 - present	Ecology and Evolution PhD Program
2019	Orygen Youth Health International Student Welfare Project Peer leader
2018 - present	Interdisciplinary PhD Program in Refugee and Forced Migration Studies
2018 - present	British Ecological Society Quantitative Ecology Special Interest Committee Member
2017 - present	QAEco Diversity and Inclusion Group Committee Member
2017	QAEco mentoring scheme Organiser
2015 - 2016	Staff-Student Consultative Committee, University of Freiburg Student Rep

# Professional experience

2016 - present	Research Assistant Dr Luke Kelly and Prof Brendan Wintle (University of Melbourne)	
2014 - 2015	Research Assistant Fraunhofer Institute for Solar Energy Systems	
2012 - 2013	Social Media Manager Creative Stirling	
2012	Intern German Embassy Colombo	
2011	Intern German Agro Action e.V. Cambodia	
2008 - 2009	Workshop coordinator Youth Educational Institute Jugendbildungsstaette Juist	

### Societies

British Ecological Society, Australian Ecological Society, BUND (Friends of the Earth Germany)

### Referees

Prof Brendan Wintle	Dr Nick Golding
MSc and PhD supervisor	PhD Supervisor
Director NESP Threatened Species Recovery Hub	Research Fellow QAEco
University of Melbourne and University of Queensland	University of Melbourne
brendan.wintle@unimelb.edu.au	nicholas.golding@unimelb.edu.au

Melbourne, May 29, 2019 Simon Kapitza